A Finding Aid to the Jacques Lipchitz papers and Bruce Bassett papers concerning Jacques Lipchitz, 1910-2001, bulk 1941-2001, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Jacques Lipchitz papers, circa 1910-1999; bulk 1941-1999; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973; Bassett, Bruce W.; 9.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-10, OV 11-12
  - Correspondence, 1926-1975; 1.2; Archival Resource Key; 4.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-5, OV 11
    - Dickinson, Edwin - Drummond, Janet Hickey, 1947-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 51)
      Dickinson, Edwin
      Dickson, Louise M.
      Dietrich, Volkmar
      Dilia Czechoslovak Theatrical and Literary Agency
      Direction Générale des Arts et des Lettres
      Dissent
      Djambatan, Ltd.
      Dobkin, Eliahu
      Documenta
      Dominique, M. C.
      Donohoe, Miss
      Dorekens, Guy
      Doren, Daniel
      Doris Weiner Gallery
      Dorra, Henry
      Dowling, Robert W.
      Downtown Gallery
      Dreyfuss, Henry
      Drummond, Janet Hickey
    - Dubaut, Pierre, 1950-1966; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 1, Folder 52-53)
    - Dubuffet, Jean - Edward MacDowell Association, Inc., 1949-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 54)
      Dubuffet, Jean
      Duda, Martha
      Duluth Herald and Duluth News-Tribune
      Duvkin, Elijah
      East Cleveland Museum Galleries
      Ecuador, Republic of
      Edelstein, Mr. and Mrs. Eugene
      Éditions d'Art Albert Skira
      Éditions des Trois Collines
      Editions Mozaika
      Edward MacDowell Association, Inc.
    - Eero Saarinen and Associates, 1952-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Eitner, Lorenz - Emery, George L., 1949-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Eitner, Lorenz
      Elgozy, Georges
      Elias, Arthur
      Ellerbe and Company, Architects and Engineers
      Ellison, Fanny McConnell
      Elsen, Albert
      Emery, George L.
    - Emery Memorial, 1956-1960, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Engle, Karen - Eytan, Walter, 1943-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Engle, Karen
      English, Virginia Shaw
      Enrico Glicenstein Memorial Committee
      Ente Manifestzioni Milanesi
      Ente Nazionale per la Protezione e l'Assinstenza dei Sordomuti
      Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States
      Errera, Paul L.
      Essex Arts
      Everett Rassiga, Inc.
      Experiment in International Living
      Eytan, Walter
    - Fairmount Park Art Association (Philadelphia), 1950-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Farber, Dorothy - F. Delius, 1952-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Farber, Dorothy
      Farmer, Walter I.
      Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, Inc.
      Farruggio, Ella Brouner and Remo
      Fauvre, Janine
      Favre, Lucien and Fela
      Fayer, Alfred
      F. Delius (F. Delius Giese)
    - Federation of Jewish Women's Organizations, Inc. - Finch College Museum of Art, 1928-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Federation of Jewish Women's Organizations, Inc.
      Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Inc.
      Feigner, John S.
      Feinberg, Charles E.
      Feinberg, Howard and Janet
      Feinberg, Margaret V.
      Feininger, Mr. and Mrs. Lyonel
      Felix Landau Gallery
      Fernand Hazan Éditeur
      Ferntree, J.
      Féron, Louis
      Ferrole, Riccardo
      Festival Foundation, Inc.
      Fields, Mitchell
      Finch College Museum of Art
    - Fine Arts Associates/Otto Gerson Gallery, Inc., 1955-1962, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fink, Frances S. - Fondation Neérlandaise des Artes Plastiques, 1948-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Fink, Frances S.
      Finkelstein, Louis
      Finocchiaro, Santo
      Fischbach, John A.
      Fischer, Harry
      Fischer, Leo
      Fischl, Bob
      Fleisig, Edith Lipchitz
      Floch, Joseph (photocopies)
      Fogel, Howard H.
      Folkes, Peter L.
      Follett Publishing Company
      Fondation Neérlandaise des Artes Plastiques
    - Fonderia d'Arte Vignali and Tommasi/Fonderia d'Arte Luigi Tommasi Pietrasanta, 1963-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ford Foundation - Foy, Hans, 1942-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Ford Foundation
      Ford, Monsieur
      Foret, E.
      Fortess, Karl E.
      Fort Worth Art Center
      Forum Gallery, Inc.
      Foshko, Josef
      Fox, William
      Foy, Hans
    - France, Republic of, 1944-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Conseiller Culturale
      Délégation du Gouvernment Provisoire
      Ministère de l'Éducation Nationale
      Ministère de Affaires Étrangère
    - Francion, L. - Franklin and Marshall College, 1951-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Francion, L.
      Francis Pratt, Inc., Primitive, Oriental, Modern Art
      Franck, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick
      Franco-American Audio-Visual Distribution Center, Inc.
      Franconia College
      Frank, Mary
      Frank Perls Gallery (Los Angeles)
      Frank, Peter
      Franklin and Marshall College
    - Franzheim, Kenneth, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Fratelli Fabbri Editori - Fry, Edward, 1943-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Fratelli Fabbri Editori
      Frederick A. Praeger, Inc., Publishers
      Freedman, Adele
      Freeman, Mr.
      French Art Theatre, Inc.
      Frenkel and Co., Inc., Insurance
      Freud, Henry
      Friedman, Frances
      Fry, Edward
    - Fry, Varian and Annette, 1944-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Fuchs, Gunter - Galerie M. Rousso, 1948-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
      Fuchs, Gunter
      Funk and Wagnalls Company
      Furman, Joyce
      Gagnon, Charles Eugene
      Galante, Francesco
      Galdikas, A.
      Gale Research Company
      Galerie Abel Rosenberg
      Galerie Chalette
      Galerie Claude Bernard
      Galerie de France
      Galerie Jeanne Bucher
      Galerie Kamer
      Galerie Louis Carré
      Galerie M. Rousso
    - Galleria del Levante - Gash, Frederick, 1949-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Galleria del Levante
      Galleria Nazionale d'Arte Moderna (Rome)
      Gallery of Jewish Art, Inc.
      Gallup, Donald
      Gamzu, H.
      Ganymed Press
      Garaventa, Lorenzo
      Garramone, Joseph
      Garti, Tess
      Gash, Frederick
    - Gaspard, Leo, 1959-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Gaugh, Harry F. - George M. Juergens Objets d'Art, 1958-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Gaugh, Harry F.
      Gaynor, Lynda
      Geilfus, Frèdèric
      Geinhers, Charles
      Geist, Sidney
      Gemeente Musea Amsterdam
      Gemeentemuseum Arnheim
      Genauer, Emily
      George Braziller, Inc.
      George M. Juergens Objets d'Art
    - George, Waldemar, 1950-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Georges-Michel, Michel - Goldwater, Robert J., 1943-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
      Georges-Michel, Michel
      Geraty, Christopher J.
      Germain, Walter
      Gertz, Ulrich
      Gilber, Miss
      Gilbert, Lynn
      Gildesgame, Leon L.
      Gittlitz, David L.
      Godenne, Ghislaine D.
      Goldberger, Blanche
      Golden, Catherine
      Goldhaft, Arthur D.
      Goldman, Elaine
      Goldring, Maurice H.
      Goldstein, Arnold L.
      Goldwater, Robert J.
    - Goll, Claire - Goodspeed, Betsy, 1944-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
      Goll, Claire
      Goodman, Moshe
      Goodman, Nelson
      Goodman, Percival
      Goodson-Todman Enterprises, Ltd.
      Goodspeed, Betsy
    - Goodwin, Philip L., 1943-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Gordon, Leah - Greenburgh Hebrew Center (Dobbs Ferry, NY), 1943-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Gordon, Leah
      Gorin, Bart
      Goutal
      Graham
      Graham, Elaine
      Grailville
      Granville-Jackson, Alastair
      Gray, Camilla
      Green, John
      Greenberg, Casserell
      Greenberg, David
      Greenberg, Joel
      Greenburgh District No. 8 Parent-Teacher Association (White Plains, NY)
      Greenburgh Hebrew Center (Dobbs Ferry, NY)
    - Greene, Marie Zoe Mercier, 1956-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Greenwich Gallery - Guerry, George P., 1926-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Greenwich Gallery
      Grippe, Peter
      Gris, Josette
      Gris, Juan
      Gris, Nato
      Gritchenko, Alexis
      Groner, Duncan
      Grosman, Tatyana and Maurice
      Gross, Chaim
      Grossman, Isidore
      Grossman, Mrs.
      Groupe O
      Gruzan, Jordan L.
      Grèguen, Pierre
      Guèdenet, Pierre
      Guerry, George P.
    - Gutnayer, Josef-Marion, Henry and Yvonne - Hammacher, R., 1949-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Gutnayer, Josef-Marion, Henry, and Yvonne
      Haarlem, Municipality of, Committee of Advice for the Monumental Arts
      Hadassah
      Hadassah Medical Organization
      Haines, Lundberg and Waehler, Architects
      Halberstadt, James
      Halter, Mrs. Joseph
      Halton family
      Hamburg, Beryl
      Hammacher, A. M.
      Hammacher, R.
    - Hammer Galleries - Harrison, Ellen, 1944-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Hammer Galleries
      Hammond, Brian
      The Hampton Day School (NY)
      Händler, Gerhard
      Haney, George J.
      Hanks, Nancy
      Hanon, Jean
      Haral, Bob
      Harbeson, Hough, Livingston and Larson, Architects
      Harding, Helen Mary
      Hari, Kenenth
      Harold J. Smith Adjusters, Inc.
      Harper's Bazaar
      Harrison and Abramovitz, Architects
      Harrison, Bebe
      Harrison, Ellen
    - Harry A. Franklin Gallery - Harry Salpeter Gallery, Inc., 1951-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Harry A. Franklin Gallery
      Harry N. Abrams Incorporated
      Harry Salpeter Gallery, Inc.
    - Harvard University - Harvard University, Fogg Art Museum, 1953-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Harvard University
      Harvard University, Dumbarton Oaks Research Library and Collection
      Harvard University, Fogg Art Museum
    - Har Zion Temple (Philadelphia) - Havey, Marguerite, 1957-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
      Har Zion Temple (Philadelphia)
      Hastings-on-Hudson, Board of Education (NY)
      Hastings-on-Hudson, Village of (NY)
      Hastings Creative Arts Council, Inc. (NY)
      Hastings, Sandra
      Haupt, William
      Hausch, W. G.
      Havey, Marguerite
    - Hay, Gyorgy [nephew] and Svetlana, 1959-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Hebrew Home for the Aged - Hill, Clinton, 1943-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
      Hebrew Home for the Aged
      Hebrew Teachers College
      Hebrew University of Jerusalem
      Hélion, Jean
      Henning, Mr.
      Henrietta M. Schumm
      Herbert, Robert L.
      Herman, Leon
      Herndon, Venable and Ursule
      Hesperia Art
      Heyer, George
      HIAS-JCA Emigration Association
      Hill, Claude
      Hill, Clinton
    - Hillside Elementary School (Hastings-on-Hudson, NY) - Hooper, Mrs. Arthur, 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
      Hillside Elementary School (Hastings-on-Hudson, NY)
      Hinkhouse, F. M.
      Hirsh, Pauline
      Hirshhorn, Joseph H. and Olga
      Hofstra College
      Hohnsbeen, John
      Holden, Jessica
      Hollander Workshop Gallery
      Holzinger, Margit
      Homburger, Freddy and Gin
      Hooper, Mrs. Arthur
    - Hope, Henry R. and Sally, 1950-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Hornik, Marcel P. - Indiana University, 1946-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
      Hornik, Marcel P.
      Hudson, Cecil
      Hudson River Museum
      Humphrey, Hubert H.
      Huntington Township Art League (NY)
      Hurleigh, Jan
      Ilin, Ephraim
      Illinois Institute of Technology, Institute of Design
      I. M. Pei and Associates, Architects and Planners
      Inaugural Committee 1961
      Indiana University
    - Ingersoll, R. Sturgis, 1946-1973; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
    - Institute of Contemporary Art (Boston) - International House-New York, 1944-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
      Institute of Contemporary Art (Boston)
      Institute of Design [formerly School of Design in Chicago]
      Institute of International Education
      International Association of Plastic Arts
      International Business Machines Corporation (IBM)
      International Congress on Religion, Architecture and the Visual Arts
      International Exhibitions Foundation
      International House-New York
    - International Rescue Committee, 1945-1968, Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - International Synagogue (John F. Kennedy Airport, NY) - Israel Museum, 1955-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
      International Synagogue (John F. Kennedy Airport, NY)
      Iona Appeal Trust
      Iona Community
      Isaacson, Philip M.
      Ish-Shalom, M.
      Israel Artists and Sculptors Association, Jerusalem Artists
      Israel Bonds
      Israel Museum
    - Italy, Il Ministro della Publica Istruzione - Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1944-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Italy, Il Ministro della Publica Istruzione
      Izdebsky, Vladimir
      Jackson, Sarah
      Jacques Lipchitz Art Foundation
      Jaffe, Benjamin
      Jaffe, L.
      Jaffe, Sam
      Jaffin, George M.
      Jafke, Orville
      Jane Wade Ltd.
      Jannoley, Adeline
      Jensen, Henry G.
      Jewish Community Center of Baltimore
      Jewish Community Center of Detroit
      Jewish Community Center of Harrisburg, Pennsylvania
      Jewish Community Federation of Cleveland
      Jewish Federation-Council of Greater Los Angeles
      Jewish Labor Committee, Women's Division, New York Region
      Jewish Museum
      Jewish Standard
      Jewish Theological Seminary of America
    - Jobling, Peter - Junior League of Tarrytown (NY), 1945-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Jobling, Peter
      John and Mabel Ringling Museum of Art
      John P. Streb, Real Estate, Insurance
      John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
      Johnson, Lyndon B.
      Johnston College
      Johnston, Stephen
      Joseph H. Hirshhorn Collection
      Joseph L. Shapiro Co., Inc.
      Joslyn Art Museum
      Julien Levy Gallery
      Junior League of Mount Kisco, New York, Inc.
      Junior League of Tarrytown (NY)
    - Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry - Katonah Gallery, 1947-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Kahnweiler, Daniel-Henry
      Kamer, Henri
      Kampleman family
      Kan, Dora
      Kaplan, Alex
      Kaplan, J. M.
      Karsh, Yousuf and Estrella
      Kasser Foundation
      Katonah Gallery
    - Kaufman, Joseph B. - Kolin, Berthe, 1942-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
      Kaufman, Joseph B.
      Kaufmann, Edgar
      Kayden, Herbert J.
      Keating, Bert M.
      Kennedy Memorial Committee
      Keren Ha'Yesod
      Kitroskaya, G. V.
      Konecky, Cyrena
      Kessler, Seymour M.
      Kieslet, Frederick J.
      King, Mr. and Mrs. George Bernard
      Klein, Elaine A.
      Kligfeld, Bernard
      Knight, Mr.
      Kohn, Hans
      Kolin, Berthe
    - Kollek, Theodore, 1961-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Koras, George - Laiken, Henry, 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Koras, George
      Koskenmaki, Joyce
      Koussevitzky, Olga
      Kramarsky, Mrs.
      Kramer, Olga
      Kramer, Robert William Mordecai
      Kramer, William
      Kriesberg, Liz and Ruth Miller
      Kroll, Leon and Florence
      Kuh, Katharine
      Kunsthaus Zürich/Musée des Beaux-Arts
      Kurz, Barbara
      Laiken, Henry
    - Landau, Gregorio, 1947-1969; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Lane, Alvin S. - La Revenaude, Annette, 1954-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Lane, Alvin S.
      Lang, Joseph
      Langley, Martina
      Langsner, Jules
      Lanagton, Basil
      Langworthy, Philip B.
      Lannelongue, Janine, Jean, and Michel
      LAR Art Objects
      La Revenaude, Annette
    - Larrea, Juan and Marianne, 1943-1972; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - La Salle College - Leuvens Unversitair Kunstcentrum, 1945-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
      La Salle College
      Lasker, Mary
      Lavaud, Bernard
      Lawrence, Michael
      Lawson, Mr.
      League for Mutual Aid
      Lecoque
      Ledoyen, A.
      Lee, Mildred S.
      Lee, Robert
      Leech, Mary V.
      Leeman, Irving
      Lefebvre-Foinet, Lucien
      Lejwa, Arthur S.
      Lemaire, Eleanor
      Le Meé, J. M.
      Lennon family
      Leofanti, Gene
      Leuvens Unversitair Kunstcentrum
    - Levering, Robert K. - Lincombe Lodge Research Center, 1947-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Levering, Richard K.
      Levin, Elliott
      Levine, Miriam
      Lewin, Henry
      Lhote, André
      Liaison des Artes
      Liberty Park Advisory Council (Los Angeles)
      Licht, Ira
      Limbour, Georges
      Lincombe Lodge Research Center
    - Lipchitz, Yulla, 1946-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Lissim, Simon - Luski, Sonia, 1947-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Lissim, Simon
      Loeb, Marjorie
      London County Council
      London, I.
      Long Island Arts Center, Inc.
      Lord, James
      Los Angeles County Museum
      Los Angeles Times
      Low, Claire B. and Frank H.
      Lowenthal, Anne F.
      Lucien Goldschmidt Rare and Fine Books, Prints and Drawings
      Luis, José
      Lusker, Louise Ganter
      Luski, Sonia
    - Lynn Farnol Group - Marks, Hylda Rose, 1943-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Lynn Farnol Group Public Relations and Information Programs
      Lyon, Emile
      Lyons, Leonard
      Lyons, Sylvia
      Magazine of Art
      Magill, James P. and Ruth
      Magriel, Paul
      Mahlow, Dieter
      Maison Nationale de Retraite des Peintres, Sculpteurs et Graveurs
      Makler Gallery
      Mandel
      Mandel, Edna Horne
      Manfred, Ernest Fred
      Mankato High School (MN)
      Marc Vaux, Photographer
      Markell, Ellis M.
      Marks, Hylda Rose
    - Marlborough-Gerson Gallery, Inc./Marlborough Fine Art, Ltd., 1957-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F2
    - Marner, Emily - McGlynn, Thomas, 1944-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Marner, Emily
      Marsh, Mrs. E.
      Martens, Michael
      Martha Jackson Gallery
      Martin, Helen
      Maslon, Lillian
      Mason, John
      Massachusetts Institute of Technology
      Massimino, Loni Ann
      Master Drawings Association, Inc.
      Mathey, Jacques
      Mathias, Mr.
      Matisse, Pierre
      May, A. Wilfred
      May, Morton D.
      Mayer, Carl
      Mazer, William
      McBride, Mr.
      MCA
      McCarthy, Mary
      McCollester, Roxane
      McGlynn, Thomas
    - Mechem, Margaret - Metcalf, Addison M., 1950-1969, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Mechem, Margaret
      Meed, Mrs.
      Meisner, Mr. and Mrs. Joel M.
      Melekian, S.
      Mellow, James K.
      Melquist, Jéròme
      Mendelsohn, Eric
      Mental Health Association of Westchester County, Inc. (NY)
      Merinoff, Dmitry
      Merkos L'Inyonei Chinuch, Inc.
      Metcalf, Addison M.
    - Metropolitan Educational Television Association, Incorporated - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1951-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Metropolitan Educational Television Association, Incorporated
      Metropolitan Museum of Art
    - Michigan State University, Kresge Art Center Gallery - Morganthau, Aline, 1944-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Michigan State University, Kresge Art Center Gallery
      Mickelson, Elmer
      Mietek, S.
      Mikoláš, Ch.
      Mikoláš, Karel
      Milch, Peggy Westbury
      Milich, Carla
      Mindlin, Henrique E.
      Minneapolis Institute of Arts
      Minneapolis School of Art
      Mishkan Le'Omanut, Museum of Art, Ein Harod
      Mission of Israel
      M. Knoedler and Co., Inc.
      Mobile Junior Chamber of Commerce
      Model, Elisabeth
      Modern Art Foundry, Inc.
      Moller, Betty
      Monaco, Principality of
      Monde Publishers, Inc.
      Montclair High School (NJ)
      Morales, Miguel G.
      Morganthau, Aline
    - Morley, Charles L. - Musée "Beit Uri et Rami Nechustan,", 1942-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Morley, Charles L.
      Moro, Francis and Thomas
      Morris and Son Construction Corp.
      Morris Gallery
      Mose, Carl C.
      Moskof, Martin Stephen
      Mosman, Mr.
      Moteo
      Mott, Hanno
      Mozer, Helen and Bill
      M. R. Schweitzer, Art Dealer - Appraiser
      Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute
      Murphy, Jo Anne
      Musée "Beit Uri et Rami Nechustan"
    - Musée Bourdelle, 1959-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Musée Cantini - Musée de l'Homme, 1946-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Musée Cantini
      Musée Châtelain
      Musée d'Art Contemporain, Skopjie (Macedonia)
      Musée de l'Homme
    - Musée National d'Arte Moderne (Paris), 1947-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Musée Rodin - Museo de Bellas Artes (Caracas), 1955-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Musée Rodin
      Museo de Bellas Artes (Caracas)
    - Museum am Ostwall - Museum of Fine Arts of Houston, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Museum am Ostwall
      Museum Bredius
      Museum Leverkusen
      Museum of African Art
      Museum of Fine Arts (Boston)
      Museum of Fine Arts of Houston
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1942-1967; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
    - Museum of Primitive Art, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Museum voor Land-en Volkendunde - National Association of Women Artists, Inc., 1945-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Museum voor Land-en Volkendunde
      Myerson-Grant, Bess
      Nadelman, Eugene
      Nadelman, Viola
      Naef, Hans
      Namir, Mordechai
      Nannucci, Maruizio
      Nathan, Fritz
      Nathan, Helmuth and Irene
      Nathan, Karl
      National Academy [of Design] School of Fine Arts
      National Association of Women Artists, Inc.
    - National Broadcasting Company, Inc. (NBC), 1957-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - National Council for U. S. Art, Inc. - National Historic Shrines Foundation, Inc., 1943-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 27)
      National Council for U. S. Art, Inc.
      National Council of Jewish Women
      National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A.
      National Educational Television
      National Gallery of Art (Washington, DC)
      National Historic Shrines Foundation, Inc.
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1961-1967; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
    - National Jewish Welfare Board - New Sculpture Group, 1943-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 30)
      National Jewish Welfare Board
      National Multiple Sclerosis Society, Westchester Chapter
      Nebenzahl, Yitzhak Ernst
      Nederlandse Kunststichting
      Neiman-Marcus
      Neumann, Hans H.
      Neumann, J. B.
      Newark Museum
      Newfield, John
      New Gallery
      Newhouse, Caroline
      Newman, Hélène S.
      Newman, Nancy C.
      Newman, Sam B.
      New Road - Novy Pout
      New Rochelle Water Company
      New School for Social Research
      New Sculpture Group